<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>urban on Christopher Prener</title>
    <link>/tags/urban/</link>
    <description>Recent content in urban on Christopher Prener</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017-2018 Christopher G. Prener</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/urban/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SOC 1120 - Introduction to Sociology: Diversity &amp; Health</title>
      <link>/courses/introsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/introsoc/</guid>
      <description>*Next Offered Fall 2019
I teach a section of Introduction to Sociology that uses health-related examples to introduce the major areas of interest in sociology. For each major topic, like social structure, race, or social class, major sociological principles are illustrated with examples drawn from the sociology of health and illness as well as allied fields like social epidemiology and public health.
The course targets pre-medicine students who are preparing for the new MCAT exam, which includes a substantive section focused on both psychology and sociology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOC 3220 - Urban Sociology &amp; The Wire</title>
      <link>/courses/urbanwire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/urbanwire/</guid>
      <description>Next Offered Fall 2020
In the past, I have taught an upper-level undergraduate seminar focused on the modern American city. Using a unique television series about Baltimore, Maryland (The Wire, which aired from 2002 until 2008), this course investigates the structural causes of urban social problems, trace their development, and explore their consequences. We discuss the interrelations between different social issues, the similarities between the experiences of Baltimore and St. Louis, and the prospects for urban social change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detrimental Influences</title>
      <link>/project/redlining/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/redlining/</guid>
      <description>This is a brand new project that I am planning to begin work on once my book manuscript Medicine at the Margins is completed. My plan is to use several new sources of spatial data to explore the intersection of historic redlining, contemporary segregation, and population health outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ecometric St. Louis</title>
      <link>/project/ecometrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ecometrics/</guid>
      <description>The Ecometric St. Louis project aims to document the effects of widespread crime, disinevestment, poverty, and segregation in St. Louis. I am specifically interested in measuring the relative &amp;ldquo;health&amp;rdquo; of neighborhoods in St. Louis by using metrics like the number of arson fires, violent crime rates, and vacant buildings. Another metric is the density of street closures in specific neighborhoods, which have been used since the 1970s to limit traffic into and out of particular neighborhoods on the city&amp;rsquo;s north side and across its midsection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>openGIS</title>
      <link>/project/opengis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/opengis/</guid>
      <description>The SLU Data Science Seminar, which Chris is a founding co-organizer of, is the host of Chris&amp;rsquo;s openGIS project. The project is a collaborative effort with SLU students to curate and host GIS data about the St. Louis area in an accessible manner. We also maintain several R packages that contain tools for working with spatial data that orginiates locally as well as more general R tools for working with spatial data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urban EMS Work</title>
      <link>/project/ems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ems/</guid>
      <description>The Emergency Medical Services (EMS) project is Chris&amp;rsquo;s original graduate research project. Begun in 2009 as a pilot study and expanded between 2011 and 2015 as Chris&amp;rsquo;s dissertation research, the project has aimed to understand the constraints on urban EMS work. In particular, Chris&amp;rsquo;s dissertation used a mix of ethnographic, qualitative, quantiative, and spatial techniques to understand how EMS work simultaneously shapes and is shaped by the neighborhoods where it occurs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>