<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GIS on Christopher Prener</title>
    <link>/tags/gis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GIS on Christopher Prener</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017-2018 Christopher G. Prener</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/gis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SOC 4650 &amp; 5650 - Introduction to Geographic Information Science</title>
      <link>/courses/introgis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/introgis/</guid>
      <description>Next Offered Spring 2019
I teach Intro to GIS at both the undergraudate and graduate levels in a combined classroom, meaning that the course has a range of students from freshmen all the way to Ph.D. levels. Like my statistics course, Intro to GIS is built around a number of common data science tools and is designed to give students a solid grounding in modern scientific computing regardless of their background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>St. Louis&#39;s &#39;Urban Prairie&#39;: Vacant Land and the Potential for Revitalization</title>
      <link>/publication/urban-prairie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/urban-prairie/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detrimental Influences</title>
      <link>/project/redlining/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/redlining/</guid>
      <description>This is a brand new project that I am planning to begin work on once my book manuscript Medicine at the Margins is completed. My plan is to use several new sources of spatial data to explore the intersection of historic redlining, contemporary segregation, and population health outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ecometric St. Louis</title>
      <link>/project/ecometrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ecometrics/</guid>
      <description>The Ecometric St. Louis project aims to document the effects of widespread crime, disinevestment, poverty, and segregation in St. Louis. I am specifically interested in measuring the relative &amp;ldquo;health&amp;rdquo; of neighborhoods in St. Louis by using metrics like the number of arson fires, violent crime rates, and vacant buildings. Another metric is the density of street closures in specific neighborhoods, which have been used since the 1970s to limit traffic into and out of particular neighborhoods on the city&amp;rsquo;s north side and across its midsection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>openGIS</title>
      <link>/project/opengis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/opengis/</guid>
      <description>The SLU Data Science Seminar, which Chris is a founding co-organizer of, is the host of Chris&amp;rsquo;s openGIS project. The project is a collaborative effort with SLU students to curate and host GIS data about the St. Louis area in an accessible manner. We also maintain several R packages that contain tools for working with spatial data that orginiates locally as well as more general R tools for working with spatial data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urban EMS Work</title>
      <link>/project/ems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ems/</guid>
      <description>The Emergency Medical Services (EMS) project is Chris&amp;rsquo;s original graduate research project. Begun in 2009 as a pilot study and expanded between 2011 and 2015 as Chris&amp;rsquo;s dissertation research, the project has aimed to understand the constraints on urban EMS work. In particular, Chris&amp;rsquo;s dissertation used a mix of ethnographic, qualitative, quantiative, and spatial techniques to understand how EMS work simultaneously shapes and is shaped by the neighborhoods where it occurs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Street Not Thru&#39;: Street Closures, Neighborhood Geography, and Local Crime Rates in St. Louis, Missouri</title>
      <link>/talk/uaa2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/uaa2018/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Closing the Gateway: Street Barriers as Public Policy in St. Louis, MO</title>
      <link>/talk/uaa2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/uaa2017/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee and Conversation - Street Barriers in St. Louis</title>
      <link>/talk/atlas2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/atlas2018/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>