<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Overview on Christopher Prener</title>
    <link>/resources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Overview on Christopher Prener</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017-2018 Christopher G. Prener</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Software</title>
      <link>/resources/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/software/</guid>
      <description>My lab utilizes a variety of software tools to make our work more organized, open, and reproducible. All of the core software we use is either free and open-source or, if it is proprietary, is a tool I can arrange access to.
Basecamp All of my projects are managed through Basecamp. This is one tool that everyone in the lab will need access to. Each lab member will be included in the PrenerHQ, where I&amp;rsquo;ll post infrequent annoucements that are general importance to everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advising</title>
      <link>/resources/advising/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/advising/</guid>
      <description>I am the primary advisor for students who are in the Computational Geospatial Science minor and also advise some Sociology majors. This section contains guidance for students who are assigned to me as advisees, and also to students who may need support from me for things like letters of recommendations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab</title>
      <link>/resources/lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/lab/</guid>
      <description>This</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macademic</title>
      <link>/resources/macademic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/macademic/</guid>
      <description>This</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting the Most out of Advising</title>
      <link>/resources/advising_overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/advising_overview/</guid>
      <description>Advising is a critical part of the undergraduate experience here at Saint Louis University. Like letters of recommendation, I find that students are often unsure of how best to utilize and prepare for advising meetings. This post is meant to provide guidance specifically to my advisees, but is generally reflective of priorities that the Sociology and Computational Geospatial Science programs have in terms of advising.
Two Advisers, One Goal Every student at SLU should have two advisers, an academic adviser in the College of Arts and Sciences (CAS), or in their home college, and a faculty mentor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab FAQs</title>
      <link>/resources/lab_faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/lab_faq/</guid>
      <description>Can I join your research team? I am always looking for motivated students who want to gain some research experience. As of Fall 2018, I do not have any additional paid positions on my research team - all involvement is on a voluntary or for credit basis. I keep an active list of the students who are working with me on my website.
What type of commitment does it take?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internships</title>
      <link>/resources/internships/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/internships/</guid>
      <description>Internships are a critical way to build skills whether you are headed to graduate school or to a job after you graduate from SLU. Internships are something that I advise all of my students to do if they can, though I recognize that unpaid internships and those that require owning a car can pose a barrier for some. Several of my students have been successful at identifying internships on-campus, which can be a great option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letters of Recommendation</title>
      <link>/resources/letters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/letters/</guid>
      <description>Letters of recommendation, or references more generally, are an important part of many internship, job, and graduate school applications. As faculty, we get requests every semester from students to (ideally) sing their praises. So, we expect you to ask! However, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that students are sometimes unsure both who to ask and how to ask.
Who to Ask Ask professors who know you well and will have a lot to say about you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>